Hey everyone, what you see here
is a Street Fighter clone that I
built using nothing but AI tools.
Everything from the animations, the UI,
the gameplay logic, were all vibe coded.
this also includes the special skills
that you see over here as well.
So in today's video, I'll be walking you
through step-by-step exactly how I went
about building this entire game, and
I did not write a single line of code.
I did not draw a single sprite.
Everything was AI-generated.
for those of you who are new to this
channel, hi, my name is Chong-U And I
believe that anybody, regardless of your
background… can learn to make games
thanks to power of AI I did a majority
of this game using Cursor and Opus 4.8.
However, I did use Codex as well as
the GPT Images 2.0 model to generate
the assets for me because these come as
part of my ChatGPT subscription as well.
I'll show you the workflow that you
would want to be taking when you're
building a game such as this and these
workflows apply regardless of the type
of game that you're trying to build.
so if you've ever wanted to learn
how to make your very own Street
Fighter-like game using nothing
but AI tools, this video is for you
Now, if you wanna get a hold of
the resources from today's video,
including the full source code of
the final game, as well as this
cheat sheet that we have here,
Check out the links in
the description below,
This will also give you access to my free
insiders club and mailing list where you
can get hold of resources such as prompts,
source code, templates, and everything
else from all of my other videos
And if you wanna take things a
step further, definitely check out
vibegamedev.com Where you'll be able to
find specialized game development agent
skills, tutorial projects including a full
written step-by-step version of today's
that you'll be able to walk through
from start to finish to get a deeper
understanding of how to go about building
games such as these So if you wanna get
hold of these different resources, check
out the links in the description below
okay, just to go into a little bit more
detail about what we'll be building today.
there's quite a few different features
that this game currently allows.
each of the characters has a
light attack and a heavy attack.
you can see the same that we have for this
jujitsu fighter on the right over here.
But the other thing that I have
also implemented is that you'll be
able to do things like blocking.
So if you try to attack the player
while he's blocked, then the
amount of damage is a lot less,
and the person is not hurt as much.
the other things that we were
able to create are all of these UI
elements that you see over here.
so the health, the player portraits,
as well as the round timers
are all showing up on screen
using custom-generated sprites.
I wanted to also highlight that I
managed to do this energy bar over here.
And once the energy bar becomes full,
you can unleash a special attack that
you see over here that has a combo.
all right, so let's get started.
I knew I wanted to make
a Street Fighter clone.
However, I wanted to have my
own visual style, characters,
as well as different mechanics.
so the first thing I did was that I
did say that I was trying to build a 2D
fighting game like Street Fighter, and
I did start off with my basic Phaser
template project that I always use.
And I said that "Consider the architecture
for a fighting game." think about the
things that we will need for animation,
gameplay logic, and collisions.
and the main thing that you see in a
fighting game is that the game is going
to be very animation-heavy because of
the different attacks that you might have
and all of the different UI elements.
once I had primed that I was
making a fighting game, Let's
focus on generating some concept
art using the image gen skill.
I did say that I wanted this to not
be too complex, recognize that this
is a technical demonstration, and
I wanted four different versions.
all right, and so here you can see
the four different mock-ups that
the image generation came up with.
this one is like a dojo.
This one is a subway, and
I really like this one.
this one is like a warehouse by the
docks, and this was the one that I
chose to go with, which is a rooftop
brawler, which is something on top of
the rooftop, but it has this really
nice cityscape in the background.
I posted this on X and asked people
to vote which one they wanted
and lots of people voted on this
so I decided to use this as the
mock-up and concept for my game
All right, so now that this one was done,
the first thing that I wanted to do was
to extract the backgrounds, from this
mock-up so what I did was that with this
mock-up, I simply prompted, the AI to give
me simply the background image without
the characters and without the UI, I
also asked it to generate the images that
were larger in length than the viewport
because this gives your characters a
little bit of room to move left and
right so that it doesn't feel so static.
and you can see here I actually
played around with a much
wider, background image.
But I felt like this was
just a little bit too long.
I just wanted to keep it simple.
and this one is just large
enough to let the characters
move a little bit off the screen.
So you can see this over here, because we
have a slightly longer background image
than the viewport, it just gives the stage
a little bit more breathing room and more
dynamism so that you are not stuck on a
single static frame I actually did play
around with asking it to separate it out
into different layers because my goal
was to have a bit of parallax effect when
the players were moving left and right.
and you can see my other video
where I actually showed you how
you can make use of parallax
layers to create a depth effect.
but in this case, I didn't have enough
time and I wanted to focus more on the
gameplay mechanics of the combat system,
so I never got around to doing it.
So the next step is to actually create the
characters that I'll be using in the game.
And so the way that I did it was I simply
went ahead and looked at all of the
different images that I had, and I asked
the AI to extract out just the character.
So in this case, I asked for the brawler
on the left-hand side for this image.
I did also play around with
using this character, but I felt
like he looked similar to this
character in terms of hairstyle.
So I, decided to go with this jujitsu
character that's sitting over here.
So with this … So you can very
simply ask AI to supply this image
and say, "I want to extract out
my characters," because I want
to use them as reference images.
And for this one I did it within Codex,
so you can see it's managed to extract the
character out of the background over here.
and you can see this is the
green boxer that I managed to
extract out along with the jujitsu
fighter that you see over here.
So that's very simple because you
can make use of image generation as
well as these mock-ups to pull all
of these out as reference images.
And the reason why you want to get
all of these reference images is
that these reference images are
going to form like the basis of
all your subsequent animations.
All right, so now we have that.
Now we go about to animating the
characters so that we are gonna
be able to put them into the game.
And for this, I made use of a tool that
I've been building called Spriterific,
And the goal of this tool that you
see over here is that given a supplied
source image, it will process it
to create a game-ready sprite that
you can then use within your game.
and I've got several videos on how
you can do this step-by-step using
any image generation model, whether
it's NanoBanana 2 or Images 2.0.
but the whole purpose of building this
tool is so that I can have a single
place that allows me to do this very
easily and to visualize the results.
So let me just show you the prompt
that I use as part of Spriteriffic.
so for example, I said, "Given the
character reference image, think
about the images that we're gonna
use." And then all I needed to do
is say, "Let's use Spriteriffic
to generate the anchor image."
This will go ahead and automatically
create what we call an anchor
image that you have over here.
So given a source image, it will
normalize everything, puts it against
a green screen and creates a neutral
facing anchor that will serve as
the basis for image consistency
for the rest of our animations.
and all I have to say is say, "Let's use
Spriterrific on the chosen anchor for the
two attack animations." And what it will
do is that it will go ahead and generate
the animations that you see over here.
and how it does so is that, first of
all, it uses Groq Imagine to create
a movie version of the animation.
So you can see that this is
the movie version over here.
The next thing it does is that it will
take out every single frame of this video
that you see over here and lay it out,
And then after that, it will go
ahead and pick a subset of these
frames and stitch it together into a
sprite sheet that you see over here.
And then that's how you get your
animation that you use within the game.
And Spriterrific is quite useful because
So you can actually pick the frames that
you want rather than using the default.
And then you can do some additional
things, such as aligning your
sprite if there's any drift.
I find that when you use Groq Imagine,
you don't actually have much drift
because it's all generated from
a video, and this already ensures
that everything looks consistent.
But it's always useful to be able to
have that level of control to be able
to adjust your images accordingly.
so you can see several
runs that I did here.
this is the heavy kick run.
this is the kick animation that was
generated from this, Groq Imagine video.
And then once I knew that it was
working correctly, I then went ahead
and said, "Go ahead and generate
all the different animations that
we would need for this game." So you
can see we have a blocking animation.
We have crouch.
we have being hit.
We have an idle animation,
and we have a jump, and then
we have a knockdown as well.
And you can see here, sometimes if your
prompt, isn't correct, can result in,
animations that don't really look right.
So in this case, he shouldn't really
be falling with his hit on the left.
I just went ahead and just re-prompted
it so that I was able to get the,
right animation that I wanted.
And you can see here I did the same
thing, with this, jujitsu fighter,
and I did do it for the boxer as
well, but I just decided not to
use this character in the game.
But you can see SpriteRefit
makes it really easy.
You can pass in the source image
and then prompt whatever animations
that you need, and it automatically,
gives you game-ready sprite sheets
that you can put into the game
I've not released SpriteRefit yet.
I'm still working on it.
But if you're interested, I put
a link in the description below
where you can register your
interest, for development updates.
So now that we've got all of
our animations, the thing that
I always like to do is to create
something called a character gem.
If you watch some of my previous
videos, you will know why I do this.
but I'm gonna go through
the key elements of a gem.
now the whole purpose of a, of a gem
is to allow you to visualize and to
debug and to troubleshoot the animation
sprite sheets that you have over
here, but in a nice single place.
So you can see over here, I can
choose whichever character I
want, and look through any of the
animations that I want as well.
the key elements are I need to see the
number of frames in the animations,
and I should be able to slow it
down, and pause whenever I want.
But the most important thing is that
we have these thing called bounds.
all of the logic is going to
be based on not on the entire
image, but on bounds or hitboxes.
in this case, you want separate
hitboxes for collision.
for example, this one will be how
the character lands on the ground.
and the main reason why this is very
important is that sometimes you will
have additional padding below your
character, and You want to make sure
that the collision of the character
with the ground looks correct so the
main bounds that you will need to have
are your collision bounds, and then
you want to have your, hit bounds.
So this will mean that as long
as there's an overlap within
this area, a hit will register.
But then this is the key one.
but this is the key one
that we have over here.
If we take a look at this punch
animation and this kick, you will
notice that the attack bounds only
becomes active at certain frames.
So at the fifth, sixth, and seventh
frame, this is where the attack bounds
actually shows up, because you don't
want the attack to register before
the character has even finished
animating his leg sticking out, okay?
And you don't want it to register
when he's withdrawing his leg as well.
this applies to all of
the different characters.
So you can see here, if I do, a heavy
kick, it only registers the attack
bounds when it is up over here.
And this allows me to adjust it slightly.
and then I can just save this.
And this editor allows you to ensure that
your characters have the right kind of
animations, and the hitboxes that you have
are activated only at the correct frames.
because you're working with spreadsheets
over here, not every single frame is
going to be relevant when it comes to
particular actions one of the main things
I learned about building a fighting
game is that if you have a blocking
mechanic, which reduces the damage,
You will want to have an additional type
of bounds called guard, because this
guard box is important because if you have
different kind of attacks, so for example,
if you have a heavy attack that kicks high
and the person ends up guarding low, you
don't want the guard to register, right?
vice versa, if you are punching at
the top and the person's guarding
low, you might want the attack to hit.
all right, so that's the character
gym, and once you've gotten hold of
that, that's pretty much the key set
of things that you will really need
to be able to get your game working.
So the other thing that I always like to
do is just before I create the main game,
is to create something like a playground.
And you can see over here, this allows
me to very quickly ensure that things
are working correctly based on what
I've configured in the character gym.
So I'm gonna turn on all the bounds that
you see over here, and you can see if
I try to do an attack here, the attack
bounce only comes out when the hand has
emerged, and the same thing for the kick.
Okay?
and the other thing that you wanna
do over here is that you want to
take this opportunity to set up
configurable parameters, so you can
just tweak the feel of the character.
sometimes you will see that the
scale of your character may be a
little bit off because of the way
that the sprites get normalized.
this allows you to very quickly
just adjust because I want this
character to be a lot larger than
what, the default scale looks like.
The other thing that you can do
is you can adjust the speed here.
I change it to a thousand, you
can see that I move a lot quicker.
And then if I change it to one, you can
see this character moves very slowly.
So this is very important
as part of game development.
AI is not gonna be able to make your
game feel perfectly right, so you want
to ensure that you have the opportunity
to tweak these parameters as well,
because otherwise, you will find
that it just feels a little bit off.
Okay?
And the main thing, that you want to
do over here, whenever you're working
with any kind of playground game, is
I always say that I want to be able
to save all of these parameters into
a JSON file, as you can see over here.
And then this JSON file is what is
loaded when the actual game starts.
All right?
So you can see all of these values
that you see over here are loaded
in from that same JSON file.
So just say you're playing the main
game now, and you've spot something
that is wrong, you can at least tweak
it straight away, and then you can save
it, and you have a consistent place to
ensure that your experience is correct.
one of the things that I realized is
that when I generated reverse walking
animations, it just didn't look right.
So I just changed the logic over
here, and I said play the walking
animation in reverse, and this
gave me a much better result.
So this is the reason why you want to
have a playground, because it allows you
to tweak and play around with how your
characters are gonna look like and how
the gameplay is gonna feel like before you
start wiring it in all within the game.
So that's the playground
that you have over there.
the next thing that I did was I just went
into Codex and said I wanted to generate
some portraits of these characters.
So you can see here, let's generate
stylized portraits of the characters
based on the reference images.
I want it to have their upper body, in
distinctive poses, and I want to use
them in a character selection screen.
and then you can see here I'm
using the Image Gen Skill.
And you can see it generated these ones
that we have over here, and this was
fairly simple to integrate into game.
so you can see I made use of these
within the character selection screen.
And this was the time where
I said I wanted to be able to
select between different levels.
I also wanted a 1v1 versus a one-
1vAI, setting.
this allows me to play against AI if you
don't have a second player to play with.
And I deliberately asked the AI to
be fairly naive here, but you can ask
your agent to make the AI a lot more
realistic, and you have a solid result
All right, so once you've got the main
menu set up, the main thing is to go
into the core combat loop over here.
this one is really just about
you going ahead and thinking
about what goes into the game.
So we add a countdown timer.
we also say that we want it such that
we have health for the characters, and
when the health depletes, as you see
over here, it starts a second round,
replenishes the health, and you can see in
this little icon that we have over here,
it means that I've won the first round.
So this is very typical
of a fighting game.
And I just said that, you know,
it's best of three matches, before
the game goes into game over.
So that's the core combat loop.
next thing to talk about
are the UI elements.
I just said, "Let's
generate a UI atlas," right?
Using image generation that
we can use for the game.
We need a health bar with appropriate
transparent areas for the health
fill and a portrait base to put
the character's portrait in.
And this is what it generated.
You can see, it's already, put
against a chroma background, so you
can then use the image generation
skill to make this transparent.
And you can see that these are
all the different elements that
it uses as part of the game.
These are the props that I
generated because I intended to
put, props in the background, but
I never got around to doing it.
And then after that, you can
simply prompt your agent to
integrate this within your game.
this was one prompt.
I said, "Let's integrate
UI elements in the game.
We should lay out the health
of the two characters and their
portraits, Make it look good.
The health bar should be dynamic and
change color based on the amount of
health left, and start blinking." this
was the effect that you see over here,
Once, the health starts depleting,
it goes from green, and then goes to
yellow, and then finally when it's
red it starts blinking, and then when
the health depletes, the character
loses and plays the death animation.
Okay, so it's really good.
I find that it does
really well in using AI.
I find that, the models are really
good at integrating UI elements.
Like you can see here, I just used
a single prompt and it was able to
get everything working correctly.
all right, so that's pretty much it.
Once you've got all of these things, you
have a complete fighting game over here.
and you can see this is a really
very decent result, and it's really
pretty fun to play, and you can
play this on the same machine.
and if you want to make this a fully
multiplayer game, you can probably use
something like Colyseus, and I've got a
whole video that talks about how you can
vibe code multiplayer functionality, very
quite easily using the Colyseus library.
the last thing that I wanted
to cover is that I wanted to
have something called specials.
and so this was the final thing that I
just wanted to have just as a nice way
to polish up what we have over here.
And in this case it was very simple.
I said I wanted to have
a special move system.
This will involve hitting a specials
button when the meter is filled.
And I did say that, I wanted to have
different specials for different
characters, and then, I said you need a
charging special animation, and then, it
should, register multiple hits as opposed
to just being a single hit, if you're
doing a special attack, So let me just
explain this in a little bit more detail.
So if I play as this character,
and I'm gonna toggle the special.
You can see over here, he's gonna do
something like a spinaroonie, and then you
can see that it registers multiple hits,
in a combo when he's able to perform his
special, and that's what I wanted to do.
Once I prompted the mechanics, it
implemented it, and then just made
use of Spriteriffic once again
to, generate all of these special
animations that you can see over here.
and then it automatically picked the
best frames stitched them together, and
then exported it out as a spreadsheet.
so this was very easy to do.
I then just tweaked it a little bit saying
that I wanted, when the specials, happens,
I wanted to show the portrait, and then
I wanted to have this lightbox effect
where the portrait comes in from the left
to give it a bit of a specials effect.
so there you have it.
That's how you can go ahead and build
your very own Street Fighter-like game
using AI, and you can just follow the
workflow that I use from start to finish,
You just wanna take things step by step.
Don't try to single problem and say, "Ah,
build me a Street Fighter clone." You'll
probably get a fairly okay result, but
whenever you're working on games, you
want to take things slowly, build things
iteratively, make sure that things look
right before you move on to the next step.
whether you're building a fighting game,
a platformer, an RPG, or whatever, is to
always have gyms, so that you can test
things like the character animations.
You can test things like the
background, And then always have a
playground, so that you're gonna be
able to test and tweak things like
the values of the mechanics as well.
All right, so that's it
for today's tutorial.
I hope you enjoyed it and learned how you
can make your very own Street Fighter-like
game using nothing but AI tools.
if you enjoyed this video, give it a
like, hit that subscribe button, and
don't forget to turn on notifications
so that you'll always be the first to
know when new content like this drops.
And if you haven't seen my other video
where I take you step-by-step from start
to finish of how you can build your very
own platformer game where you can collect
items, fight enemies, and have a level
progression, you definitely wanna check
out this video that you see over here.
All right.
Till next time, I'll see ya